<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shinichi Urano&#39;s personal blog</title>
    <link>https://urano.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shinichi Urano&#39;s personal blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://urano.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Cult</title>
      <link>https://urano.me/posts/cargo-cult/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://urano.me/posts/cargo-cult/</guid>
      <description>(Ceremonial cross of John Frum cargo cult, Tanna island, New Hebrides (now Vanuatu), 1967) There&amp;rsquo;s a growing trend today in using &amp;ldquo;Cargo Cult&amp;rdquo; as an adjective to form various idioms, most likely started by Richard Feynman in this speech to coin &amp;ldquo;Cargo Cult Science&amp;rdquo;.
It loosely means &amp;ldquo;form without substance&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually much more than that. Here&amp;rsquo;s Feynman&amp;rsquo;s description of Cargo Cult:
 In the South Seas there is a Cargo Cult of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>77 paths to “Totality” and how I got there</title>
      <link>https://urano.me/posts/77-paths-to-totality-and-how-i-got-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://urano.me/posts/77-paths-to-totality-and-how-i-got-there/</guid>
      <description>The Great American Eclipse is less than a week away.
The hype for this particular event is partly due to the large swath of places (mostly across the United States) where one may witness the so called ‘totality.’ This is when the moon covers the entire sun, producing the ‘total’ eclipse.
During totality, the sun is completely covered, and it gets as dark as night. And you can actually see the corona surrounding the sun as in the image above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I could’ve been “Dimwit”</title>
      <link>https://urano.me/posts/i-couldve-been-dimwit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://urano.me/posts/i-couldve-been-dimwit/</guid>
      <description>People often ask me what my first name (Shinichi) means, as it is unusual outside of Japan. But I’ve always struggled a bit in answering this simple question.
In Japan, naming a newborn is serious business. Many Japanese can tell you several reasons behind their names, and how those reasons come together in meaningful ways. So explaining a name is not so simple. It’s a story.
My name also has a little story behind it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Manager/Bad Manager</title>
      <link>https://urano.me/posts/good-manager/bad-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://urano.me/posts/good-manager/bad-manager/</guid>
      <description>In the spirit of Ben Horowitz’s Good Product Manager/Bad Product Manager, here’s my attempt at Good Manager/Bad Manager, summarizing lessons from my ten years trying to get this right.
Good managers are all about their teams. They measure themselves through the successes of their teams. They are tirelessly driving to create environments where the team members are fully engaged and doing great work. Good managers remove obstacles and create room. Good managers work to understand and develop each worker as individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I drink beer out of the bottle</title>
      <link>https://urano.me/posts/why-i-drink-beer-out-of-the-bottle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://urano.me/posts/why-i-drink-beer-out-of-the-bottle/</guid>
      <description>I have a friend who always insists on having his beer poured into a glass to drink.
I on the other hand almost always drink out of the bottle. (Though, yes, with polite company, I do try to act move civilized.)
It’s not laziness that I do this — it’s actually hero worship, for my dad.
You see, my dad grew up in post-war Japan. Life was hard back then. He grew up in a neighborhood in Osaka that had mostly burned down during the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why every CIO needs to look at DevOps</title>
      <link>https://urano.me/posts/why-every-cio-needs-to-look-at-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://urano.me/posts/why-every-cio-needs-to-look-at-devops/</guid>
      <description>Software is eating the world. That’s how Netscape founder Marc Andressen describes it.
It’s always been obvious that so-called high-tech companies live and die by their technological prowess. What is becoming more evident today is that we’re entering an era where all companies must compete by their technological prowess.
There are headline-grabbing stories that herald this era. Netflix vs. Blockbuster is a recent example. Driven by technology, a disruptive start-up took over an industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps - It&#39;s solving the right problem</title>
      <link>https://urano.me/posts/devops-its-solving-the-right-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://urano.me/posts/devops-its-solving-the-right-problem/</guid>
      <description>When thinking about building an IT solution (or a business for that matter!) I&amp;rsquo;m often reminded of this delightful article by Aza Raskin: You Are Solving The Wrong Problem.
It describes the insight that helped the late Paul MacCready solve the problem of human-powered flight and win the Kremer Prize. The winning aircraft, Gossamer Condor, can now be found at the Smithsonian Air and Space Museum and is pictured here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>